MATTHEW TRAN

mattran161091@gmail.com | Australian Citizen | Fluent in English and Teochew

SUMMARY

Highly-motivated individual with extensive food and beverage knowledge and who is passionate to provide exceptional customer service. Over four years working in the hotel industry, with two years supervising a Japanese restaurant which has a proven track record of winning awards within the first year of operation.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

2012-2013	Bachelor of Business	(International Tourism	and Hotel Management)
2012-2013	Dacifetol of Dubilless	IIIILEI II ALIOIIAI TOULISIII	anu notei manayement

Griffith University

Grade Point Average: 5.81 (Scale: 1 - 7, with 7 the highest)

2010-2011 Diploma of Tourism

Southbank Institute of Technology

2004-2008 Year 12 Queensland Certificate of Education

Brisbane State High School

QUALIFICATIONS

2015	MOEI	Level	o iii Sake

2014 Responsible Service of Alcohol Certificate (RSA)

2010 Travelport Certificate

Southbank Institute of Technology

2010 Crosscheck Travel Enterprise Client Management Certificate

Southbank Institute of Technology

2008 Certificate II in Business

2008 Japanese Certificate 3

TECHNICAL SKILLS

I have developed and acquired the following technical skills in the industry:

- Competent in Opera, the reservation system for hotels and Micros (Point of Sale) system for restaurants
- Competent and experienced in using airline reservation systems such as Galileo and Amadeus in the tourism industry
- Able to use Microsoft Office, Powerpoint and Excel

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Mar 2017 - Nov 2017 Mandarin Oriental Tokyo - Mandarin Oriental, Tokyo is a five-star luxury hotel with views to take your breath away. Exuding crisp, contemporary style, we pride ourselves on our excellent technology, renowned spa, innovative restaurants and impeccable service.

Title: Food and Beverage Attendant

Responsibilities and skills developed:

- Sound knowledge of food, wine and cocktails
- Opening and closing of morning, lunch and dinner service
- Providing efficient and courteous service
- Ability to communicate effectively with a variety of customers and create a positive experience
- Ability to work well within a international team environment
- Ability to work under pressure and without supervision
- Following instructions from chefs and managers
- Constantly maintaining a high level of personal grooming and presentation

Nov 2014 - Dec 2016 Jupiter Hotel and Casino - Jupiter Hotel & Casino is your premier entertainment destination set in the heart of Australia's stunning Gold Coast.

.....

Title: Captain (Full Time)

Responsibilities and skills developed:

- Providing training for staff and assisting management to develop training programs to grow a service focused team while driving revenue and productivity
- Leading, supporting, motivating and engaging with staff members
- Highly organized, dedicated and passionate to continuously find ways to deliver exceptional guest service experiences
- Ability to communicate with a variety of guests ranging from local/international tourists to corporate guests
- Responding and dealing with guest feedback and complaints
- Assisting with planning and liasing with guests for events and private functions
- Extensive food and beverage knowledge
- Liaising with head chef and sous chef to ensure special requests are met and meals arriving in a timely manner
- Good knowledge of alcohol legislation to ensure laws and regulations are not breached

Dec 2012 - Nov 2014 Treasury Hotel and Casino Brisbane - Treasury Hotel and Casino Brisbane is the entertainment destination in the Brisbane CBD.

Title: Food and Beverage Attendant at Fat Noodle

Responsibilities and skills developed:

- Sound knowledge of food, wine and cocktails
- Ensuring the opening and closing of restaurant
- Experienced in using POS (Point of Sale) systems, such as Micros
- Developed effective interpersonal and communication skills
- Ability to communicate effectively with a variety of customers and create a positive experience
- Ability to work well within a team environment

Jan 2011 - Dec 2011

Mindpearl - Global provider of outsourced customer contact solutions delivering excellence in customer care to many of the world's leading companies

Title: Virgin Australia Airline Reservation Agent

Responsibilities and skills developed:

- Creating/amending bookings for international passengers from the USA, UK, Australia and to destinations throughout Europe
- Operating Airline Reservation Systems, primarily Amadeus
- Assisting with flight delays and disruption procedures to ensure travelers reach their destinations
- Answering queries regarding tourist destinations such as Los Angeles, London and Abu Dhabi
- Informing guests of correct check-in times, baggage allowance, visa and passport requirements to international destinations such as Los Angeles, Abu Dhabi and the UK
- Keeping up to date with the latest tourism products/services offered for international passengers
- Handling and dealing with international guest complaints
- Meeting and achieving monthly KPI
- Following Airline protocols and regulations
- Following instructions from Team Leaders and Supervisors

ACHIEVEMENTS

Sep 2014

Urban List Barista, Waiter and Cocktail Awards 2014

Nominated in the top 20 finalist list for waiter of the year in Brisbane.

Dec 2013

Griffith Award for Academic Excellence

The Griffith Award for Academic Excellence is awarded to both the University's undergraduate and postgraduate students in recognition of their academic achievement. This award recognises consistent academic achievement in 2013 with a GPA of 6.0 or greater, which places the student in the top 5%.

May 2011

Southbank SALT Travel Seminar 2011

Title: Event Staff and Planner

Responsibilities in this role included:

- Assisted in organising of the event, such as creating promotional flyers
- Setting up of equipment for guests and assisting guest speakers with the use of presentation equipment
- Creation, distribution, collection and analysis of surveys for future tourism events

RESUME - Matthew Tran

SKILLS AND ATTRIBUTES

- Effective written communication skills, including writing clear and concise reports (as demonstrated by gaining distinctions and above for university assignments)
- Strong oral communication skills (developed through oral presentations for university assignments)
- Ability to communicate with people at all levels (as a result of working in customer service roles for many years)
- Highly-developed analytical and research skills (as a result of academic studies)
- High level of organisational skills
- Excellent teamwork skills gained through work and team projects for university